Software Engineer & Backend Web Developer (Typescript)

Ottawa, Ontario, Canada

📞 4387737407 🗷 dellali.salim@gmail.com 📓 linkedin.com/in/dellalisalim 🏶 https://salimdellali.netlify.app

Software Engineer & Backend Web Developer by passion and profession, with years of experience in websites, web apps, and web services development. Working mainly with the Javascript ecosystem (specializing in Node.js Backend Development), and focusing on delivering high quality solutions by following as many web development best practices as possible. Always excited about learning new and developing current soft and technical skills, both on the professional and personal levels.

Work Expertise

The development stack actively used is focused mainly on the **Javascript ecosystem**. The main technologies are:

- Programming languages: Javascript -Typescript
- Backend: Node.js Express.js -NestJS
- Databases: Prisma MongoDB MySQL
- Version control: Git GitHub
- Tools: **VSCode Postman Jira**

Languages

- English: full professional proficiency (listening, speaking, writing and reading)
- French: full professional proficiency (listening, speaking, writing and reading)
- Arabic: professional proficiency (listening, speaking, writing and reading)
- Russian: professional proficiency (listening, speaking)

Working Experience

Intermediate Backend Javascript Developer at Combyne Ag - Canada [MAR 2023 - MAR 2024]

Combyne Ag (Medium-sized startup of 30 employees) [Acquired by BAYER], is a crop marketing management app that empowers farmers to make quick and easy grain marketing decisions, with all their information in the palm of their hands.

Combyne Connect - product of Combyne - is an API ecosystem that farmers are able to use to connect Combyne to both their farm tools and buyer tools, and to bring their relevant crop marketing data all together in a single place.

Being part of the Combyne Connect Team, as a Backend Javascript Developer, my duties were:

- With the help of 2 teammates, build Combyne Connect API from scratch using NestJS framework
- Write unit, integration and e2e tests using Jest for Combyne Connect API
- Write Swagger documentation for Combyne Connect API
- Participate in writing "black box" automated test using Mocha and Chai for Combyne Connect API

While working at Combyne, the key achievements were:

✔ Build from scratch and deploy the first version of Combyne Connect API

Main technologies used at Combyne Ag

Typescript · Node.js · NestJS · Prisma · AWS Cognito · Swagger · Jest · Jira · RESTful API · Git · GitHub · VSCode · Postman · Slack · MacOS

Software Engineer & Backend Web Developer (Typescript)

Ottawa, Ontario, Canada

4387737407

dellali.salim@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/dellalisalim

https://salimdellali.netlify.app

Fullstack Web Developer at <u>YASSIR (YC W20)</u> - Algeria

[MAR 2022 - FEB 2023]

YASSIR (Medium-sized startup of +100 employees) is the leading super App for on-demand and payment services in French-Speaking Africa, offers on-demand services such as ride-hailing, last-mile delivery, and financial services to help users pay, save and borrow digitally.

Being part of the Shared and Financial Services Engineering Team, as a Backend Developer, the duties were:

- Developing new features and fixing bugs
- Writing documentation to help new developers integrate quicker into the team
- Coordinating with the Engineering Manager and Product Managers to agree upon projects' specifications
- Writing automated tests for the RESTful API
- Participating in the recruitment process of new developers by technically interviewing them

Main technologies used at YASSIR

Typescript · Node.js · Express.js · MongoDB · Mongoose.js · Jira · RESTful API · Git · GitHub · VSCode · Postman · Slack · MacOS

Javascript Developer at Data Impact By NielsenIO - Algeria [SEP 2021 - JAN 2022]

Data Impact (Medium-sized startup of +100 employees) is A powerful, collaborative analytics platform that helps brands interpret and master their omnichannel data. Real-time e-store data and advanced A.I. algorithms offer actionable insights and clear strategic guidance for optimized execution across an organization.

Being part of the Engineering team, the duties were:

- Maintaining a proper execution of the data analytics dashboard
- Working with legacy Javascript code
- Hunting and fixing bugs, cleaning the code
- Coordinating with Product Owners
- Helping Product Owners detect bugs
- Participating in releases to the pre-production and production environments
- Coordinating with other teams such as PHP and GO developers about data transfer
- Participating in recruiting new developers

Main technologies used at Data Impact

Javascript ES6 · VSCode · Jira · Git · BitBucket · Slack

Self-taught MERN Stack Developer - Home

[APR 2020 - SEP 2021]

Upleveling Web Development skills during the pandemic, exploring further JavaScript and learning the MERN Stack through tutorials and side-projects.

During the lockdown, had the chance to deep dive into the Javascript ecosystem. the key achievements were the development of:

✔ Frontend Web Projects:

- Personal Website & Portfolio: https://salimdellali.netlify.app
- Dummy React Conference Website: Built as a Jamstack Website using React.js,
 React-router-dom, Formik, and React-bootstrap as UI library
 - Live demo link: https://dummy-react-conf-website.netlify.app

Software Engineer & Backend Web Developer (Typescript)

Ottawa, Ontario, Canada

📞 4387737407 🗷 dellali.salim@gmail.com 🛅 linkedin.com/in/dellalisalim 🏶 https://salimdellali.netlify.app

- GitHub repo: https://github.com/salimdellali/dummy-react-conf-website
- Dummy React Conference Dashboard: Built as a Jamstack Website using React.js,
 React-router-dom, Redux, Formik, and Material-UI as UI library
 - Live demo link: https://dummy-react-conf-dashboard.netlify.app
 - GitHub repo: https://github.com/salimdellali/dummy-react-conf-dashboard

✓ Backend Web Projects (RESTful APIs):

- Dummy React Conference Server: built using Node.js, Express.js, JWT, MongoDB, and Mongoose
 - Live demo link: https://dummy-react-conf-server.onrender.com
 - GitHub repo: https://github.com/salimdellali/dummy-react-conf-server
- Parking Lot Server: built using Node.js, Express.js, Typescript, In-Memory Storage, and Jest
 - Live demo link: https://parking-lot-server.onrender.com
 - GitHub repo: https://github.com/salimdellali/parking-lot-server
- Text Storing and Processing: built using Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, and Mongoose
 - Live demo link: https://text-storing-processing.onrender.com/text
 - Github repo: https://github.com/salimdellali/text-storing-processing

Main technologies learned

Javascript ES6 · Gulp.js · Npm · MongoDB · Express.js · React.js · Node.js · Mongoose.js · Typescript · Redux · Axios · Sass · React-bootstrap · Material-ui · Styled-components · Git · Github · JWT · Jest · RESTful API · Postman · WebStorm · VSCode · Netlify · Heroku

Fullstack Web Developer at Médiafex - Algeria

[FEB 2019 - MAY 2020]

Médiafex (Small-sized business of 10 employees) is a Communication Consulting and Web Agency founded in 1999 by Mr. Mohamed Boumala, the core activities of Médiafex are graphic design, building search engines about companies, producing advertising objects and corporate gifts, producing advertising signages, and providing internet services such as web development and web hosting.

As a Fullstack Web Developer, the duties were:

- Gathering Mr. Boumala's requirements to build websites and web services
- Coordinating with a graphic designer to create assets for websites development
- Developing websites and web services
- Coordinating with Mr. Boumala and reporting periodically the advancement status of websites and web services
- Daily news publishing on https://www.annugate.com, owned by Mr. Boumala

While working at Médiafex, the key achievements were:

- ✔ Building a presentational Website for exposing Médiafex company and it's services
- ✔ Build a Website with a complex search in large catalogs for Line-x Algeria (Line-x Algeria being a company of waterproofing, thermal insulation and protective coating solutions and services, owned by Mr. Boumala)

Main technologies used at Médiafex

HTML5 · CSS3 · Javascript ES5 · PHP · MySQL · Bootstrap · JQuery · FileZilla · CPanel · Git · BitBucket · PhpStorm

Software Engineer & Backend Web Developer (Typescript)

Ottawa, Ontario, Canada

4387737407 ■ dellali.salim@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/dellalisalim https://salimdellali.netlify.app

Wordpress Web Developer at Feel Safety

[OCT 2018 - JAN 2019]

Feel Safety (Small-sized business of 10 employees) is specialized in wholesale distribution of personal protective equipment and fire fighting equipment.

As a Wordpress developer, the duties were:

- Build new features for the Feel Safety website : https://www.feelsafety-dz.com using Wordpress Technology
- Fix bugs, and ensure the proper and smooth execution of the website
- Participate in improving the User Interface and User Experience (UI/UX) of the website
- Populate, update and remove products for the online shop on the website

Education & Certificates

Masters degree in Software Engineering - Algeria

[SEP 2015 - JUN 2017]

At <u>USTHB</u> (University of Science and Technology Houari Boumedienne)

Master's degree Canadian Equivalency by <u>WES</u> (World Education Services)

[SEP 2023]

Bachelor degree in Computer Science - Algeria

[SEP 2012 - JUN 2015]

At USTHB

Clean code Certificate - Udemy

[JUN 2021]

By Maximilian Schwarzmüller, link certificate:

https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-9261a691-5200-4c56-bae6-1cc4a2614d71/

CELPIP English Exam Certificate

[NOV 2023]

Speaking: 9, Listening: 10, Reading: 10, Writing: 10

Volunteering experience

<u>AIESEC</u> - Local Committee Benak, Algeria

[OCT 2014 - MAY 2018]

AIESEC is a global platform for young people to develop their leadership potential through practical experiences of many kinds, including internships, volunteering opportunities, and more. Founded in 1948, AIESEC is a non-governmental and not-for-profit organization entirely run by youth, for youth.

While a student, had the chance to join AIESEC, one of the largest youth movements in the world. The positions held during the AIESEC journey were: Team Member Designer, Team Member Talent Management (TM) Tracking, Team Leader TM Tracking, AIESEC Products Promoter, TM Department Vice President. Ended my journey by becoming an AIESEC Alumnus.